Adam Weiler

adam.weiler3@gmail.com

(647) 961-3890

www.linkedin.com/in/adamweiler

Cybersecurity Enthusiast

Motivated, critical thinker with a background in web development interested in solving complex cybersecurity problems. Experienced in the use of Python and JavaScript, possesses knowledge in identifying risks, building defensible systems, and determining threat landscapes.

SUMMARY OF KEY QUALIFICATIONS

- Acquired a working knowledge of security principles, risk assessments, and best practices
- Cooperated with teams to achieve goals and meet deadlines in a fast-paced environment
- Focused under pressure and time constraints by prioritizing tasks appropriately
- Developed a strong understanding of operating systems, internet, and network protocols
- Gained experience in troubleshooting and debugging network issues
- Learned different ways to approach successful problem solving

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Security Concepts

- Network packer analysis
- Password auditing
- Command injection
- Network scanning
- Intrusion detection
- Hashing
- Automating file integrity checks

Security Tools

- Kali Linux
- Metasploit
- Tcpdump and Nmap
- Wireshark
- Aircrack-ng
- John the Ripper
- Cain and Abel
- Snort

Web Development Skills

- JavaScript
- Python 3

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

Accelerated Cybersecurity Training Program - Rogers

Cybersecure Catalyst, Brampton - AUG 2020

• Intensive 24-week course combining self-study and in-class training through 3 SANS courses, CyberStart, SEC401 Security Essentials, and SEC504 Hacker Techniques and Incident Response

Certified Incident Handler (GCIH) - GIAC - AUG 2020

• Demonstrated qualification for detecting, responding, and resolving computer security incidents

Security Essentials (GSEC) - GIAC - MAY 2020

• Demonstrated qualification for hands-on IT system roles with respect to multiple security tasks

General Assembly, Toronto – Web Development - SEP 2019

• Intensive 12-week course combining interactive lectures and solving real-world problems by building full-stack applications

Durham College, Oshawa - Web Development - APR 2008

• Two-year program covering web development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL, Photoshop, and Flash

Adam Weiler

adam.weiler3@gmail.com

(647) 961-3890

www.linkedin.com/in/adamweiler

PROJECTS

SongFeels - React, Django, Third-Party API, CSV database, Bootstrap - OCT 2019

- Built web application to search third-party API for song lyrics, compare to a database of 14,000 words, and use a custom algorithm to identify emotions displayed
- Secured API key to ensure others could not impersonate license holder https://songfeels.herokuapp.com/

CarbCount - React, Django, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap - SEP 2019

- Built web application for diabetic users to log in, search third-party API for nutritional information, and calculate how much insulin is required after eating
- Secured API key to protect license holder from unlawful use

Crowdfunder - Django, SQLite3, CSS - AUG 2019

• Built web application for users to log in and create personal projects in order to crowd-source funds

WORK EXPERIENCE

Client Assistant – Seniors Life Enhancement Centres, Oakville - SEP 2015 - FEB 2019

- Collaborated with a team of 10 staff members to support 60 clients by analyzing their unique needs and recommending appropriate activities
- Secured confidential information on web applications and documented clients' progress.
- Ensured premises remained safe and secure

Freelance Web Developer - Self-Employed, Online - SEP 2008 - DEC 2009

- Established secure FTP connection to clients' severs to ensure confidentiality of data
- Implemented website design changes for international clients

Graphics and Web Designer – *University of Ontario Institute of Technology, Oshawa* - SEP 2006 - AUG 2008

- Designed and developed 3 websites to meet specifications provided by a Forensics professor
- Established secure FTP connection to University severs to ensure confidentiality of data
- Handled sensitive materials and requested permission to use external files from owners
- Wielded tools such as Photoshop, Illustrator, and Dreamweaver